<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hi, I'm Max 👋 on Max Rodrigo</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/</link><description>Recent content in Hi, I'm Max 👋 on Max Rodrigo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.maxrodrigo.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Install Alpine Linux on Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/how-to-install-alpine-on-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/how-to-install-alpine-on-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>Preparation Download the Raspberry Pi build.
Which version should I install?
TL;DR: Unless you are using Raspberry Pi 2 Model B or Raspberry Pi Zero, install aarch64.
There are currently three versions of Alpine for Raspberry Pi: armhf, armv7, and aarch64.
You should be safe using the armhf build on all versions including Pi Zero and Compute Modules, but it may perform less optimally on recent versions of Raspberry Pi.</description></item><item><title>Escaping strings in Bash</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/escaping-strings-in-bash/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/escaping-strings-in-bash/</guid><description>A couple of days ago, An interesting thread came up on HN about escaping string in Bash using !:q.
As Pascal Hirsch describes on Twitter, the idea is simple: after an expression, use !:q to escape the given string.
$ # This string &amp;#39;has single&amp;#39; &amp;#34;and double&amp;#34; quotes and a $ $ !:q &amp;#39;# This string &amp;#39;\&amp;#39;&amp;#39;has single&amp;#39;\&amp;#39;&amp;#39; &amp;#34;and double&amp;#34; quotes and a $&amp;#39; bash: # This string &amp;#39;has single&amp;#39; &amp;#34;and double&amp;#34; quotes and a $: command not found How does this work?</description></item><item><title>Homelab Buying Guide</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/homelab-buying-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/homelab-buying-guide/</guid><description>Things I wish I&amp;rsquo;d known It is Expensive! It is an expensive hobby and it does not end when you get a server. For multiple servers you will need switching; if you have many cables, a patch panel will be necessary and probably a router. Covers, trays, cable managers, PDUs, UPSs, and the list goes on and on. Electricity is something to consider too and there are many factors involved: usage, UPSs, power redundancy, your &amp;ldquo;Power Mode&amp;rdquo; configuration, etc.</description></item><item><title>Survival Guide to IRC identification</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/survival-guide-to-irc-identification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/survival-guide-to-irc-identification/</guid><description>NickServ is the utility used for registration and protection of nicknames. It allows users to register, and prevent others from using it.
For a deeper understanding of the service, I recommend using the online HELP.
/msg NickServ help [&amp;lt;command&amp;gt;] Important Note: If a registered nickname is not logged in for 30 days, NickServ will drop the account, making it available again. If using Freenode, see their Policies.
Register a nickname /msg NickServ REGISTER &amp;lt;password&amp;gt; &amp;lt;email-address&amp;gt; Most servers require a valid email address that they will e-mail with a verification code.</description></item><item><title>Install Puppeteer and Chrome on Amazon Linux</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/install-puppeteer-and-chrome-on-amazon-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/install-puppeteer-and-chrome-on-amazon-linux/</guid><description>For most of our frontend deploys, whether is a QA or a prerender stage of the pipeline, we intensively interact with Chrome for their automation. Here&amp;rsquo;s part of the provisioning script to install Puppeteer, Chrome and its dependencies on an AWS EC2 Amazon Linux AMI.
#!/bin/env bash # Install 3rd party repositories sudo rpm -ivh --nodeps http://mirror.centos.org/centos/7/os/x86_64/Packages/atk-2.22.0-3.el7.x86_64.rpm sudo rpm -ivh --nodeps http://mirror.centos.org/centos/7/os/x86_64/Packages/at-spi2-atk-2.22.0-2.el7.x86_64.rpm sudo rpm -ivh --nodeps http://mirror.centos.org/centos/7/os/x86_64/Packages/at-spi2-core-2.22.0-1.el7.x86_64.rpm # Install dependencies sudo yum install -y nodejs gcc-c++ make cups-libs dbus-glib libXrandr libXcursor libXinerama cairo cairo-gobject pango libXScrnSaver gtk3 # On Amazon Linux 2 Downgrade ALSA library sudo yum remove alsa-lib-1.</description></item><item><title>Python HTTPS Simple Server</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/python-https-simple-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/python-https-simple-server/</guid><description>Many times Netcat1 is enough for a single-use transfer, but when sharing multiple files or even a website, Python offers a simple yet powerful solution.
Python&amp;rsquo;s HTTPServer, or SimpleHTTPServer in Python 2, serves as a quick and easy way to start a local HTTP server on your network.
NOTES
http.server is not recommended for production. It only implements basic security checks.
Python 2 is deprecated and should be avoided if possible.</description></item><item><title>Instalación y configuración de TinyDNS [ES]</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/instalacion-y-configuracion-tinydns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/instalacion-y-configuracion-tinydns/</guid><description>TinyDNS es el servidor de nombres de djbDNS, una suite de herramientas para DNS, creada por Daniel J. Berstein. Por defecto el servidor solo responde a consultas de las zonas previamente declaradas, no responde consultas inversas ni transferencia de zonas. Para estas otras funcionalidades otra serie de herramientas estan disponibles dentro de la suite. Esta modularidad lo hace muy potente, versatil y rápido.
djbDNS se compone de 6 herramientas:
TinyDNS: Servidor de Nombres.</description></item><item><title>Disable Current Shell Session Input History</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/disable-current-shell-session-input-history/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/posts/disable-current-shell-session-input-history/</guid><description>If you work a lot in the terminal you may recognize the input history, aka history, as a major productivity boost, even if you use the arrow keys to navigate throw it. We need to understand that the history buffer is not committed until you log out, so everything you see when running the history command is not yet written to disk.
To avoid the current input history to be saved we should unset the HISTFILE environment variable.</description></item><item><title>Bookshelf</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/bookshelf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/bookshelf/</guid><description>Some of the books, videos and other resources I consider noteworthy.
Is also a good place to thank all my friends and mentors who helped me in this adventure of learning.
Books Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs
By Harold Abelson, Gerald Jay Sussman, Julie Sussman
1979 UNIX and Linux System Administration Handbook
By Evi Nemethm, Garth Snyder, Trent R. Hein, Ben Whaley
2010 Clean Code
By Robert Cecil Martin</description></item><item><title>Luis Maximiliano Rodrigo Zubieta - Curriculum Vitae</title><link>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/curriculum-vitae/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maxrodrigo.com/curriculum-vitae/</guid><description>Date of birth July 25, 1985 Email contact@maxrodrigo.com Website www.maxrodrigo.com LinkedIn /in/maxrodrigo/ Revised Nov 1, 2021 Summary With over two decades immersed in the tech world, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a front-row seat to its many transformations and evolutions, providing me with a unique lens on the tech ecosystem. My profound love for technology is matched by my drive to build high-performing teams and spearhead transformative projects. By seamlessly merging innovation with execution, I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently turned visions into realities.</description></item></channel></rss>